<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science and Analytics Portfolio on Enrique Bar贸n G贸mez</title>
    <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science and Analytics Portfolio on Enrique Bar贸n G贸mez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NLP: TF-IDF Movie Recommender</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>For this project I created a python Web App that uses a TF-IDF model of the genres and keywords of movies and cosine similarity, that measures the similarity between two non-zero vectors, to recommend five movies to the user, given a movie the user likes. For this task, I used a dataset from TMDB (The Movie Database) that contains 5000 movies, with their respective genres and keywords, between the year 1916 to 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML: Country Religion Classifier</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>For this project I created a classifier to correctly identify the religion of a country given its geographical location, its area in square kilometers, its population in millions of people, its language and the characteristics of its flag such as its color and the shapes that appear on it, like: circles, crosses, sunstars, crescents, saltires, triangles, etc&amp;hellip; For this task, I used the flags dataset from the repository of Machine Learning of the University of California Irvine which contains information of 194 countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Endangered Species in United States National Parks</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from the US National Parks Service about endangered species in different parks. Taking the role of a biodiversity analyst, the goal is to ensure the survival of at-risk species to maintain the level of biodiversity within the parks. In that sense, I will identify if there are any patterns in the types of species that become endangered and their relationship to the National Parks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Life Expectancy and GDP</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data on the Growth Domestic Product (GDP) and Life Expectancy from the World Health Organization and the World Bank, to try and identify the relationship between the GDP and the life expectancy of six countries. GDP is the total monetary or market value of all the finished goods and services produced within a country&amp;rsquo;s borders in a specific time period. In that sense, being a broad measure of overall domestic production, it functions as a comprehensive scorecard of a given country&amp;rsquo;s economic health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: FIFA World Cup Data</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from the FIFA World Cups between 1930 and 2014. This tournament is an international football competition where countries qualify to send teams made up of the best players from each nation to obtain the World Cup Championship. It has been awarded every four years since the inaugural tournament in 1930, except in 1942 and 1946 when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t held due to the Second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me through these platforms.
   Platform    URL     Email . . . enriquebaron27@hotmail.com   LinkedIn . . . https://www.linkedin.com/in/EnriqueBaronGomez/   GitHub . . . https://github.com/princeKike27    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
