<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Enrique Barón Gómez</title>
    <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Enrique Barón Gómez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Endangered Species in United States National Parks</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from the US National Parks Service about endangered species in different parks. Taking the role of a biodiversity analyst, the goal is to ensure the survival of at-risk species to maintain the level of biodiversity within the parks. In that sense, I will identify if there are any patterns in the types of species that become endangered and their relationship to the National Parks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Life Expectancy and GDP</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data on the Growth Domestic Product (GDP) and Life Expectancy from the World Health Organization and the World Bank, to try and identify the relationship between the GDP and the life expectancy of six countries. GDP is the total monetary or market value of all the finished goods and services produced within a country&amp;rsquo;s borders in a specific time period. In that sense, being a broad measure of overall domestic production, it functions as a comprehensive scorecard of a given country&amp;rsquo;s economic health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML: Prediction of Honey Bee Production Decline in the US </title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from honey bee production in the US from 1998 to 2012. As you may have heard, honey bees are in a precarious state right now, news and articles are informing about the decline of the honey bees population and the impact it will cause on the entire planet. This is because, honey bees are the world&amp;rsquo;s most important pollinator of food crops. It is estimated that one third of the food that we consume each day like avocados, soybeans, asparagus and kiwis rely on bees pollination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: FIFA World Cup Data</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from the FIFA World Cups between 1930 and 2014. This tournament is an international football competition where countries qualify to send teams made up of the best players from each nation to obtain the World Cup Championship. It has been awarded every four years since the inaugural tournament in 1930, except in 1942 and 1946 when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t held due to the Second World War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python: Magic-8 Python Ball</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>For this project I created a Python implementation of the Magic 8-Ball game. The Magic 8-Ball is a popular toy developed in the 1950s for fortune-telling or advice seeking. The user asks a yes–no question to the ball, then turns it over to reveal an answer in a window on the ball. It was invented in 1950 by Albert C. Carter and Abe Bookman and is currently manufactured by Mattel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics: Roller Coaster Data</title>
      <link>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://princekike27.github.io/Enrique_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>For this project I analyzed data from the best ranked wooden and steel Roller Coasters in the world between 2013 to 2018. Roller Coasters are thrilling amusement park rides designed to make you squeal and scream! They take you up high, drop you to the ground quickly, and sometimes even spin you upside down before running to a stop. Roller Coasters are often split into two main categories based on their construction material: wood or steel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
